Someone sent me the access password last night.
（ミゼルカ）ゆうべ　何者かが　私に
アクセスパスワードを送ってきたの。
それを使って　本部のコンピューターに
アクセスしたら…。
And when I logged in to HQ's computers with it...
私たちに関する　機密ファイルよ。
These are our confidential files.
（ダウト）何だと！？
（雷鳴）
What?!
残酷で…　滑稽な真実…。
The truth's so cruel it's almost comical.
lost te saguri de sagashiteta
Lost, trying to find it blindly with my hands.
tozasareta mirai no kotae nante doko ni mo nai
But the key to the locked future is nowhere to be found.
hashiru shoudou ima kaidoku funou
Undecipherable urges surging.
found kudaketa hazu no unmei wo
I found the fate I believed broken.
mijukuna yume no naka de kikoetekitan da
I heard it in my immature dream.
saigo made I'll be there for you
I'll be there for you till the very end.
tachitomaranai kono hari dake wa
I can't stop. I hear nothing else.
boku no asu wo kizamu oto tsukisasu
How this needle carves my future.
shinjitsu kara nigetara ima
I'm running away from the truth now.
genjitsu ni mo maketara ima
I'm losing to reality now.
nani ga nokoru no (nokoru no)
What will be left?
kazoekirenai kono kizu dake ga
The countless scars on my body
boku no kinou wo zanzou toshite kataru
are the only thing telling the story of my past.
unmei ga hodokete mo ima
Even if fate falls apart now,
sonzai wo kowashite mo ima
even if existence shatters now,
boku no michi wo yuku yo
I'm walking down my own path.
It's now or never.
This is what they say: "Live your life today."
There will always be, there will always be a way.
The Sad Clown
カイト！　解けたの？　愚者のパズル。
Kaito, did you solve the Fools' Puzzle?
エレナ　もっとハードな
愚者のパズル　教えろ！
Elena, take me to more difficult Fools' Puzzles!
こんなんじゃ　全然
手ごたえが　ねえ！
This is nowhere near enough!
（エレナ）そ　それは　かまわないけど。
I don't mind, but...
（ギャモン）少し　ハイペースすぎや
しねえか？　無理は　命取りだぜ。
Aren't you going a bit too fast?
Your life's on the line.
悠長なこと
言ってらんねえんだよ。
I don't have time to take it easy.
フリーセルは…　レプリカリングを
本物にしちまった。
Freecell turned his replica ring into the real thing.
やつと　ゲームをするためには→
If I want to win a game against him,
I gotta get stronger!
俺は　もっと
強くならなきゃいけねえんだ。
カイト…。
Kaito...
（キュービック）嫌なデータだな。
愚者のパズルを解くたびに→
I don't like this data...
He's showing the same pattern as when
he was on his way to becoming a Phi Brain.
ファイ・ブレインになりかけた時と
同じパターンが…。
カイトは…　どこへ
行こうとしてるんだろう？
I wonder where Kaito is heading...
何ですって！？　本気なの？　ダウト。
What? Are you serious, Doubt?!
ああ　私は　大門カイトに
最後のゲームを挑む。
Yes.
I'll challenge Daimon Kaito to one last game.
なぜ　いまさら？
But why would you do that now?
They've been tricking us and treating us like tools all this time!
私たちは　今日まで
道具扱いされてきたのよ！
偽りを…　信じさせられて…。
We were forced to believe their lies...
それが　クロンダイク様のご意志ならば
ミゼルカ　お前は　どうする？
If that's Lord Klondike's wish...
Mizerka, what are you going to do?
うっ。　私は…　うっ。
I...
Melancholy!
メランコリィ　戻ってきたの？
She's back!
心配してたのよ。　あはっ。
I was so worried...
ミゼルカ…。
待ってて。　メランコリィにも話してみる。
Mizerka...
Wait here, I'm going to talk with her.
リングのことは　伏せておくね。
（扉が閉まる音）
I'll skip the part about the rings, though.
Melancholy?
メラン…　コリィ…。
やあだ。　もう。
お姉様ったら　面白すぎる！
Oh, please!
You're just too funny!
な　何が　おかしいの？　メランコリィ。
Is something wrong, Melancholy?
ねえ　お姉様　お姉様の親友
イブって人　実験体だったのよね？
Say, that best friend of yours, Eve-
she was just some lab experiment, right?
うっ！　どうして　それを！？
How do you know that?!
（メランコリィ）リングが　レプリカとも知らず
さんざん利用されて→
She did her job not knowing her ring was a replica,
用が済んだら　ぽいっ！
かわいそうな人。
and when she was no longer useful, she was thrown away.
How pitiful.
あたしは行かないわ。
お姉様と一緒にしないで。
I'm not going. Don't put me in the same league as you.
何なの！？　その言い方！
Why are you talking like that?
Stop this foolishness and come with me!
いいから　あなたも
一緒に来なさい！
聞いてるの！　メランコリィ！
はっ！
Are you listening, Melancholy?!
ちょっと　何様のつもり！？
実験体のくせに。
Just who do you think you are?!
Lab rat!
はぁ！
ホント　鼻につくのよね　その姉ヅラ。
Your big sister obsession is annoying as hell.
私は　妹なんて思ったこと
一度もないのに。
I've never once considered you my sister.
うぅ…。
遊びよ　遊び。
It was all just a game.
あなたが　おせっかいの
世話焼きだから遊んであげただけ。
You're too damn annoying, so I played along with you.
メ…　メランコリィ…。
M-Melancholy...
さようなら。　レプリカ・リングのお姉様。
Goodbye, Big Sister of the Replica Ring.
（ダウト）メランコリィは？
And what of Melancholy?
I... I want to be relied on by someone.
（ミゼルカ）私は…　私は　誰かに
必要とされる存在でありたい…。
「一緒に来い」。　そう言われれば…
私は行くわ。
Tell me to come with you, and I will.
来てくれ。
Come with me.
Okay.
（ホイスト）
お話は　まとまったようですね。
I see you've decided.
ホイスト！　貴様！
今まで　一体　どこに！？
Whist!
Where the hell have you been?!
Lord Klondike will be overjoyed to see that you have devoted yourselves to the Orpheus Order
真実を知ってなお　その身を
オルペウス・オーダーにささげる→
お二人のご決意　クロンダイク様も
いたく　お喜びです。
even after learning the truth.
いっ…。
ダウト様　お望みならば→
Sir Doubt, I can upgrade your ring if you wish.
リングをアップグレードして
差し上げましょう。
何だと！
より強大な力を…。
What?
It gives greater power.
フリーセル様や　ピノクル様も
そうされましたように…。
Just as it did for Sir Pinochle and Sir Freecell.
Would you look at that...
（バロン）おや？　これは…。
What an unusual guest.
珍しいお客様ですね。
私　やっぱり　おかしいと思う。
I still think it's really strange that you're challenging Fools' Puzzles for Freecell's sake!
フリーセル君のために
愚者のパズルを解くなんて。
だから　言っただろう！
I already told you!
フリーセルは　限りなく
ファイ・ブレインに近づいてんだ。
He's infinitely close to becoming a Phi Brain!
やつと戦うためには…。
カイトもファイ・ブレインになるっていうの？
To fight him...
Are you going to become a Phi Brain yourself?
自分から拒否したファイ・ブレインに…。
違う！　そうじゃねえよ。
The same Phi Brain you rejected?
No, that's not it!
（アナ）でも　アナが思うに
愚者のパズルは→
But I think... the Fools' Puzzles were built to train the Phi Brain.
ファイ・ブレインを育成するためのパズル。
The Phi Brain waits at the end of the path you're following.
行きつく先は　ファイ・ブレイン…。
I... Well...
そ　それは　そうだけど…。
でも　俺は　もっと強くなんなきゃ。
Either way, I gotta get stronger!
（ダウト）ならば　我々が相手になろう。
オルペウス・オーダー！
Then you can fight us.
The Orpheus Order!
ダウト！　何しに来やがった！
Doubt! What are you doing here?!
大門カイト。　我々と戦え。
Daimon Kaito! Fight us!
何だと！？
（キュービック）ああっ。
What?!
Get lost! Didn't you say you'd never return if you lost the fight?!
ざけんな！　決闘に負けたら→
二度と　手だし　しねえんじゃ
なかったのかよ！
約束を破んのか　てめえ！
すまない。　騎士道精神に
もとる行為だと自らを恥じている。
I'm sorry. I'm ashamed to say that I need to disobey the rules of chivalry.
カイト！　彼らのリングは本物じゃない。
レプリカだ！
Kaito, their rings aren't real! Those are replicas!
（ミゼルカ）
そうよ。　私たちのオルペウス・リングは
データ収集を目的としたレプリカ。
That's right.
Our Orpheus Rings are replicas made for the purpose of gathering data.
私たちは　ファイ・ブレインの
子供なんかじゃなかった。
We've never been children of the Phi Brain.
単なる実験体…。
We're just lab rats.
（ダウト）
昨日　オルペウス・オーダーの機密ファイルを見て
我々も　それを知った…。
We found out yesterday when we saw the Orpheus Order's classified documents.
貴様たちには　さぞかし　愚かで
哀れな道化師に見えるだろう。
I imagine we appear as foolish, pitiful clowns to you.
But my loyalty won't falter.
だが　私の忠誠心は揺るがない。
クロンダイク様の偉大なる計画の
礎となるならば→
If I can be a part Lord Klondike's great plan,
喜んで　この身をささげよう。
I will happily devote myself to that.
お前　どうして？
Why would you...?
クロンダイクに　だまされてたのに
どうして？！
He tricked you, so why?
心の声
やはり　２人とも
リングに飲まれてる。
They're both being overwhelmed by their rings.
ん？　これは！？
心の声
What's this?
ミゼルカの思考に乱れが…。
There's a disturbance in Mizerka's thought pattern...
なんだ？　このノイズは？
心の声
What's this noise?
（ダウト）
あと数％のデータが　そろえば→
With a few more percentage points,
レプリカ・リングは　ファイナル・リングとして
完成する。
the replica ring will be completed and become a final ring.
そのためのデータを　我々が収集し
クロンダイク様にささげる。
We will gather that data and offer it to Lord Klondike.
そして　その相手は
貴様をおいて他にない。
For that purpose, you will be our opponent!
戦え！　大門カイト！
Fight, Daimon Kaito!
命を懸けたゲームで　我らと！
Fight us in a game with our lives at stake!
冗談じゃねえ！　そんなゲーム
やれっかよ！　いまさら　お前らと。
Forget it! Why would I-
（バロン）受けてあげても
よいのではありませんか？
You might as well accept the challenge.
彼らは　恥辱に耐え
全てを告白したのです。
They endured the shame and confessed everything.
ギャモン君　君が
パズルを作ってください。
Gammon, you should make a puzzle.
おっさん！
言われなくても　そのつもりだぜ。
Old man?
You don't need to tell me.
そいつらの墓場となるパズルを
作ってやる。
I'll make a puzzle fit to be their grave.
ギャモン君！
アントワネット　手伝え。
Gammon!
Antoinette, help me out!
わ　分かった。
ち　ちょっと　何なのよ？　それ。
Okay!
What are you talking about?
ＰＯＧジャパンの敷地をお貸しします。
パズルは　そこに。
I'll allow you to use a POG Japan facility for the puzzle.
Thanks.
感謝…。
もう　どいつも　こいつも！
One after another! Are you all nuts?!
あんたたち　みんな
バッカじゃないの！
何かしら？
Do you need something?
Eve...
イブには…　お姉ちゃんには…
あなたが必要…。
My sister needs you.
いいえ。　私は　もう
必要とされていないわ。
No. I'm not needed anymore.
私は…　負けない。
I won't lose.
カイト…　アナ…。
Kaito... Ana...
いいパズルだ。
This is a good puzzle.
さすが　私が認めた男　逆之上ギャモン。
As expected from the man I acknowledged, Sakanoue Gammon.
This puzzle will be your coffins.
（ギャモン）
てめえらの棺桶となるパズルよ。
鉄骨もろとも落下して
くたばりな。
You'll fall and be buried under the steel.
（ダウト・無線）
「貴様は戦わなくていいのか？」。
You're not going to fight?
ああ　死にたくねえからな。
Yeah. I don't wanna die.
（ギャモン・無線）「カイト　アナ　全力で潰せ！
でないと　てめえらが死ぬぞ！」。
Kaito, Ana, fight with all you've got,
or you're dead!
分かってる。
はいは～い。
I know.
Sure thing!
救えるのか？
心の声
リングに飲み込まれ→
Can we save them?
They're overwhelmed by their rings,
心の声
オルペウス・オーダーに忠誠を誓う
あいつらを…。
and being pulled on strings by the Orpheus Order...
やるっきゃねえ！
パズルタイムの始まりだ！
No choice!
It's puzzle time!
（カイト・アナ）べぇ！
（ダウト）行くぞ！
Let's go!
アナも行くぞ～！
I'm going too!
よっ。　ほっ…　よっと。
（エレナ）
心の声
やっぱり…　恐ろしいパズルね。
This is a truly dreadful puzzle.
プレーヤーは　縦横
心の声
鉄骨１本分だけ　移動できる。
The players can move one bar at a time vertically or horizontally.
ただし　他人のいる
心の声
鉄骨には移動できない。
However, they can't move to a bar where someone is already standing.
同じ鉄骨にとどまる
心の声
ステイは　１回だけ。
You can only stay on a bar for one turn.
You can't stay for two or more.
心の声
２回連続のステイは　認められない。
落とせる鉄骨は　最大３本。
You can drop up to three bars at a time.
一直線に並ぶ鉄骨だけを
心の声
落とせて→
You can only drop bars in a row,
他人が乗っている列の
心の声
鉄骨は落とせない。
and no bar from a row where someone stands.
当然　パズル本体と
心の声
接していない鉄骨は崩れ落ちる。
Of course, bars not connected to the puzzle will fall.
心の声
そして　１人でも相手の乗っている
鉄骨を落とした方が勝ち。
And if you can make at least one of the opponents fall, you win.
速い！　迷いが　ねえ！
They're fast! No hesitation at all!
They're strong.
強えな　あいつら。
リングの力だね。
It's the power of the rings!
That's not all.
（バロン）それだけではないでしょう。
死をも恐れぬ使命感と忠誠心が…。
They're filled with loyalty and sense of duty; death is nothing to them.
アナ！　頼む！
Ana! It's yours!
Okey dokey!
いいとも～！
う～ん！　あっちかな？
こっちかな？　そっちかな？
This way? That way? Or that way?
そっち～！
That way!
な～んちゃって
やっぱり　こっち～！
Just kidding! This way!
（ミゼルカ）無意味な手を！
相変わらず　不愉快な子。
That move is pointless.
He's unsettling as always.
あっ。　不愉快…。
Unsettling...
Stop... It's okay.
（イブ）
回想
やめて…　もういいの…　もう…。
イブは　あの子を許した…。
Eve... forgave him.
私が…　あの子を憎む理由は　何？
Why do I hate him?
He doesn't have a choice!
選択肢を奪われた…。
いい手だ…　ミゼルカ。
えっ！？
Good move, Mizerka.
私は　ステイ。　ただし…。
I stay.
However!
えっ。
（ダウト）何を迷っている？　大門カイト。
Why do you hesitate, Daimon Kaito?
己の全てをかけて　我らを潰せ。
さもなくば　我らが貴様を潰す！
Fight and defeat us with everything you've got,
or else we're going to defeat you!
言われなくても！
カイト…　本気じゃないよね？
No need to tell me!
Kaito... isn't serious...
本気で戦わなければ　彼らを
救うことはできません。
うっ。
He can't save them unless he's serious.
あいつらを本当に救えるのか？
俺が…。
Can I really save them?
（アナ）カイト！
あっ。
Kaito!
アナが思うに　何にも考えない！
えっ！？
I think... you shouldn't think!
Don't think, just enjoy the puzzle to its fullest!
何にも考えず　思いっきり
楽しむんだな！　パズルを。
アナ…。
Ana...
そうだな…　どうせやるなら
楽しくやってやるぜ！　パズルをよ！
You're right!
If we're already at it, let's have some fun with this puzzle!
俺も　ステイだ！　そして！
I stay too! And...
（爆破音）
何ですって！
What?!
ミゼルカの張った罠に気づくとは…
さすが　大門カイト…。　だが…。
He noticed Mizerka's trap?
He lives up to his name. But...
Not yet!
まだまだ。
ぴよ～ん。
我らの有利は　揺るがぬ！
ああ　そうかよ！
We still have the upper hand!
You sure about that?!
行かせない！
ぽよよ～ん。
I won't let you!
なにっ！
（爆破音）
What?!
Nice, Ana!
いいぜ！　アナ！
イエ～イ！
Yay!
流れが変わったぞ！
ええ！
The flow's changed!
Kaito!
カイト～！
If he hadn't moved to that beam,
（ダウト）今　あいつが
心の声
移動した鉄骨を　私が落とせば→
大門カイトは落下していた。
心の声
I'd have dropped him and Daimon Kaito with him.
それを完璧に読み切り
妨害するために→
To foresee and avoid that,
心の声
大門カイトだけでなく
アナ・グラムまでもが…。
not only Daimon Kaito, but Ana Gram are both...
Wonderful. So they are the true children of the Phi Brain.
すばらしい！　これが
心の声
真のファイ・ブレインの子供たちなのか！
You look like you're having fun, Doubt.
（ミゼルカ）楽しそうね　ダウト。
楽しい？　そうだな。
パズルは楽しい。
Fun?
I am, this puzzle is fun.
ミゼルカ　お前も楽しそうだな。
Mizerka, you seem happy too.
あっ。　私は　ダウトが「来てくれ」って
言ってくれたから…。
That's because you told me to come with you.
幼い頃から　私は
誰にも必要とされなかった。
Ever since I was young, no one has ever needed me.
そんな自分が大嫌いで　ずっと
変わらなくちゃと思って→
I hated myself for that and always wanted to change.
生きてきた。　うれしかったわ。
I'm really happy.
I see.
そうか。
（爆破音）
あっ。　大門カイト～！
Daimon Kaito!
Let's finish this!
決めるぜ！
うっ　ステイよ。
Stay!
やっほほほ～！
（ダウト）くっ！　ステイだ。
（爆破音）
I stay.
俺も　ステイだ。
I stay too.
カイトの次の一手で　終わりだ。
Kaito's next move will end it.
くっ…　もはや　ここまでか。
So this is the end?
見事だ　大門カイト。
Well done, Daimon Kaito.
I don't consider it shameful to lose to you.
貴様に敗れるのならば
私には何の悔いもない。
あっ！
（ダウト）さあ　とどめを刺せ…。
End it now!
Quickly! End it!
早く！　とどめを！
（ミゼルカ）私は　いや！
I don't want to...!
いや…　私は　死にたくない！
I don't want to die!
生きて　もっと　もっと
パズルを解きたい！
I want to live and solve more puzzles!
ミゼルカ！
ダウト　あなたも　そうよ！
Mizerka?!
Doubt, I know you feel the same!
Right? I won't believe you if you say otherwise!
そうでしょう？
違うとは言わせないわ！
You looked so happy while solving the puzzle!
パズルを解いていたときの
楽しそうな　あの笑顔…。
あれが　本当のあなた！
うっ！
That's the real you!
どうして…　どうして　自分が
自分のままじゃいけないのよ～！
Why... Why can't we be ourselves?!
あっ。
ミゼルカ！
Mizerka!
This is the pity of a knight... No, a samurai.
騎士の…　いや　武士の情けだ。
このエリアの電波遮断システムは　完璧。
収集データも送信されていません。
The radio isolation system of this area is faultless.
They couldn't send the gathered data.
ですね。
あっ　あんたらね！
Yep!
Would it hurt to say stuff like that beforehand?!
先に言いなさいよ～！
あっ。
大丈夫？　しっかりして。
Are you okay? Hang in there.
（ピノクル）ダウト　君が　笑顔で
パズルを解くのを　初めて見たよ。
Doubt, that was the first time I've seen you happy while solving a puzzle.
P-Pinochle?
ピ　ピノクル…　生きていたのか…。
You're alive?
いい笑顔だった。　やっぱり　君も
パズルが好きだったんだね。
It was a nice smile.
You loved puzzles too, didn't you?
ミゼルカに　パスワードを送ったのは
僕だよ。
I sent Mizerka that password.
よかった…　君たちも救われて…。
I'm glad... You've been saved too.
ダ　ダウト…。
D-Doubt?
逆之上ギャモン。
ああ…。
Sakanoue Gammon.
Huh?
I still don't feel one bit of shame for using your sister.
俺は　今も恥じてはいない…
お前の妹を利用したことを…。
（殴る音）
あぁ。
ギャモン！
Gammon!
You bastard!
てめえ！
すまなかった…。
I'm sorry.
いてぇ…　ふっ。
うっ…　お前…　フッ。
The hell...
I think... Mizerka wished for this.
アナが思うに　ミゼルカは
こうなることを…→
リングに　さよならして
救われることを願ってたのかも…。
For saying goodbye to the ring and being saved!
僕も　そう思う。
I think so too.
あの思考の乱れは
その思いの反映だったんだ。
That must've been the noise in her thought pattern.
（アナ）
イブお姉ちゃん　喜ぶだろうな…。
Eve will be happy too!
（クロンダイク）
メランコリィ　私は　お前が妬ましい。
Melancholy, I envy you...
そのリングを持つ　お前が…。
I envy you for having that ring.
（ドアの開く音）
ん？　来たか…。
Finally here?
私の計算どおりだよ。
Just as I thought.
eiyuu kidori itsu datte shinjita muteki no kankaku
I think I'm a hero and believe that I'm invincible.
tatakatte iru no wa chikyuu no tame nanka janai
I'm not fighting for the world.
motto mai peesu de
It's for a more personal,
sou motto shoujikina negai no tame
a more honest wish.
nando to naku kizutsuite mo
No matter how many times I'm hurt